Bekir Shabutov

Full Stack Engineer

💌 arillaxe@gmail.com 🔭 arillaxe.dev 🛭 in /in/bekir-shabutov 😭 github.com/Arillaxe 💡 Antalya, Turkey

PROFILE

Passionate software engineer specializing in web application and service development, DevOps, and UX/UI design. With over 5 years of professional experience I helped build various projects across different product domains including ad-tech, blockchain, e-commerce, AI platforms and more.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer, Causal Foundry

Jun 2023 - Mar 2024

• Developed frontend client for a ML data analytics platform using React and SCSS.

Remote

- · Created an Operations Platform for a medical supply app with React.
- Fully reworked company's landing website using Vue and SCSS.

Full Stack Engineer, DataMilk

Nov 2022 - May 2023

 Implemented automated tests system with slack alerts to monitor widgets on customers websites using Cypress, WebDriverIO, Selenium.

Remote

- Developed front-end service for widget configuration using React and Next.js.
- Developed a URL classification tool to help categorize raw URL data into useful groups for ML models.
- · Worked following Agile Scrum methodology.

Full Stack Engineer, Waves Enterprise

Sep 2021 - Nov 2022

• Developed blockchain web client for Waves Enterprise blockchain platform using React and Remote Mobx.

- Developed API for the web client using Nest.js, Sequelize, TypeORM, PostgreSQL.
- Developed stable coin smart contract using Nest. is and gRPC for Waves Enterprise blockchain platform.
- Implemented cross-domain authentication.
- Developed oracle service for the blockchain platform using Node.js.
- Developed authorization management system app (frontend + backend).
- Worked following Agile Scrum methodology.

Full Stack Engineer, Private startup

Jan 2019 - Aug 2021

Remote

Refactored internal UI lib, added unit tests, storybook and documentation.

- Developed admin dashboard with complex table structures using React and Meteor.js.
- Developed Node.js scripts/CLI for report generation based on raw analytical JSON data and Hadoop/Hive.

Junior Front-End Developer, Yandex

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

• Developed an admin panel to edit business information displayed in search results using BEM, React, Express, MongoDB.

Simferopol, **Russian Federation**

Worked following Agile Scrum methodology.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering, Crimean Federal University

Sep 2017 – Jun 2021 Simferopol,

Russian Federation

LANGUAGES

English | Russian

SKILLS

TypeScript | React | Next.js | Nest.js | Node.js | Redux | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Redis | Vue | JavaScript SCSS | MUI | Figma | Docker | gRPC | MobX | Jest | Cypress | Selenium